美国二十世纪福斯电影公司
出品
TSG娱乐公司
联合出品
15年前，一项科学实验的失误，造就了超智商猿类的           …
事故引起的病毒使得人类几近灭亡，人们将这种病毒称之为猿流感。
崛
起
黎明
猿类的           在凯撒的领导下曙光初现，幸存下来的人类试图与猿类文明和平共处…
可猿类的叛徒科巴为了报复人类，最终发动了攻击，人类与猿类之间的战争最终还是打响了。
黎
明
战
争
人类向驻扎在北方，美国最后的军队发送了求救信号，军队闻讯赶来，一名冷酷无情的上校
率领着一支久经沙场的特种部队前来消灭猿类。在过去的两年里，他们一直未能抓获凯撒，
有人传言他在树林深处建立了秘密基地，已经为           做好了准备…猩火即将燎原…
战
争
之
极
终
：
起
崛
球
猩
猴子杀手
该闭眼了 猴崽子
濒危物种
上尉
Cap.
驴子
那是个战壕吗
Is that a trench?
里面好像还有好几只
It looks like there's more of them inside.
E26呼叫指挥
Echo 2-6 to command.
上校  北面树林发现三只金刚  其中一只有武器
Colonel, we've got eyes on 3 kongs in the north woods. One of them is armed.
驴子发现了另一条战壕  基地可能就在附近
Our donkey just spotted another trench. Maybe the base is near.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
是 长官 收到 完毕
Yes, sir. Copy. Over.
嘿 驴子
Donkey.
普里彻
Preacher.
带枪的那个
The one with the gun.
- 把他放倒之后 拿下战壕  - 是 长官
- As soon he guns him down, you guys take out the trench. - Yes, sir.Yes, sir.
开火
Fire!
冲啊
Come on!
给我箭
Reload.
撤退 撤退
Fall back!
上校 收得到吗 上校
Colonel, do you copy? Colonel?
- 你是谁  - 我是普里彻 长官
- Who is this?  - Preacher, sir. Preacher.
你在哪里 士兵 告诉我你的位置
Where are you, soldier?I need your position.
- 我不知道  - 那你能看到什么
- I don't know. - What do you see?
什么都看不到 长官  我们损失惨重 上尉他牺牲了
I can't see anything, sir. We lost a lot of men and captain is dead, sir.
- 行了 冷静点 现在由你指挥  - 由我指挥吗
- Calm down. You're in command now. - Command, sir?
我想现在只剩下我一个人了
I think it’s just me by myself now.
上校 我想我可能坚持不住了 长官
Colonel, I don’t think I'm gonna make it, sir.
我很抱歉 真的很抱歉 长官
I am sorry. I am so sorry, sir.
听着 杀死一只是一只
Listen to me. Kill as many as you can.
不 不 不
No. No, no!
死了63个
63 dead.
你是他 你就是凯撒
You are him. You're Caesar.
我们找了你很久了
We've been searching for you for so long.
传说你有一个秘密基地 可我们一直都没能找到
We heard you had a hidden command base, but we could never find it.
有人说你可能已经死了
Some of us were starting to think that you might be dead,
可麦卡洛上校说你一定还在某个地方
but the Colonel McCullough said you were out here somewhere.
- 杀了我们得了  - 闭嘴
- Just kill us already. - Shut up, man!
怎么了 他们是畜生 他早晚会宰了我们的
What? They're animals. He's gonna slaughter us.
战争并不是由我挑起的
I did not start this war.
始作俑者已经死了
The ape who did is dead.
他叫科巴
His name was Koba.
是我杀了他
I killed him.
- 现在 我只是想要保护我的同类  - 是吗
- Now I fight only to protect apes.  - Yeah?
那么他呢 还有其他10个像他这样的
What about him? We got ten more just like him.
我知道这些家伙 他们跟随科巴
I know these apes. They followed Koba.
他们想要杀了我
They tried to kill me.
他们害怕我会报复他们
They fear what I will do to them.
所以
So now
他们选择为你们做事
they serve you?
为了生存下去
just to survive.
我并不怕你
I no fear you!
你才应该害怕
You must fear!
你觉得这片树林还能保护你们多久
How long you think woods can protect you?
人类会消灭你们
Humans destroy you.
他们的上校非常强大
Their Colonel has all power.
对他们而言 他不是一个普通人
For them, he more than just human.
他掌控一切
He everything.
他说先杀了凯撒
He say: "First Caesar die?
接下来就轮到你们了
then all of you die."
温特 把这叛徒带出去
Winter! Take this traitor outside!
怎么处置这些人类
What should we do with the humans?
你要放我们走
You are letting us go?
告诉你们上校 你见到我了
Tell your Colonel, you have seen me now.
我还有句话要你带给他 只要人类退出树林
And I have a message for him. Leave us the woods?
杀戮就能够停止
and the killing can stop.
你觉得他们会把话带到吗
Do you think they will give him the message?
他们本身就是消息 毛里斯
They are the message, Maurice.
他会知道我们并不是野蛮人
He will see we are not savages.
那个叛徒袭击了我 被他逃走了
The traitor attacked me! He got away!
科巴始终阴魂不散
Koba still haunts us.
为什么当时我看不出 他根本无法原谅人类对他做的事
What I didn't see that he could not forgive what humans did to him.
没人知道他的内心
No one could have known how much darkness...
有多么黑暗
was living inside him.
父亲
Father!
欢迎回家 火箭
Welcome home, Rocket.
你看上去很累
You look tired.
- 这次路途非常遥远  - 父亲 我们有发现
- It was a long journey. - Father, we found something!
走吧
Come.
母亲
Mother!
科尼利厄斯 和你哥哥打个招呼
Cornelius... Say hi to your brother!
孩子 快看那是谁
Look who's here, son...
蕾可
Lake...
就是这个地方 父亲 我们可以重新开始 一个新家园
This is it, Father. We can start over. A new home.
- 那些山后面是什么 孩子  - 让大家看看 火箭
- What is beyond those mountains, son? - Show them, Rocket.
一片沙漠 那里离这儿很远
A desert! The journey is long...
也正因为这样人类才不会找到我们
But that is why humans will not find us.
我们今晚就得出发
We must leave tonight!
今晚 这怎么可能
Tonight? That's impossible.
- 我们还能熬多久 蕾可 士兵已经逼近了  - 温特
- How long can we wait, Lake? Soldiers getting closer! - Winter...
你的儿子离开太久了 凯撒
Your son's been gone, Caesar...
他不知道我们有多艰难
He doesn't know how hard it's been.
我知道你很害怕
I know you are scared...
我们都一样
We all are...
可我们还得计划一下
But we are still planning...
没错 我们得找个安全的方法离开树林
Yes. We must find a safe way out of woods.
之前因为只有你们两个
There were only two of you.
可现在目标太大了
But we are many.
我们会找到办法离开这里的
We will find a way out of here.
团结才会强大
Apes together strong.
待在这儿 孩子 保护好你的母亲和弟弟
Stay here, son. Protect your mother and brother!
凯撒 出什么事了
Caesar! What's wrong?
有多少兄弟在巡逻
How many on patrol?
- 五六个吧  - 把他们找来
- Five? Six? - Get them!
卢卡 把火箭也找来
Luca, get Rocket too.
L4呼叫指挥 上校
Unit calling command. Colonel...
- 火箭 发生什么事了  - 我听到他说的话了 上校就在这里
- Rocket? What happened? - I heard him talking! Colonel is here!
99 目标已击毙
Ninety-nine, target acquired.
99 目标已击毙 重复 金刚已经死了
Ninety-nine, target acquired. Repeat, King Kong is dead.
我们走 赶紧撤离这里
Let's go. I get up from here.
凯撒 温特不见了
Caesar... We can't find Winter!
他之前很害怕 我想他背叛了我们
He was scared! I think he betrayed us!
找到科尼利厄斯了吗
Have you found Cornelius yet?
我们还在找
We're still searching.
我们去找凯撒的小儿子
Let's go look for Caesar’s little son.
科尼利厄斯
Come, Cornelius.
你安全了
You're safe now.
蕾可
Lake.
你爱我的儿子
You loved my son.
在我回来之前 照顾好他的弟弟
Look after his brother, until I return.
你不和我们一起去新家园吗
You're not coming with us to our new home?
不
No.
跟着蕾可
Go with Lake.
凯撒 你该不会想要去找他们吧
Caesar! You're not going after them?!
不是他们 是他
Not them, him.
凯撒 你是我们的首领
Caesar, you are our leader!
我们不能没有你
We can't leave without you!
我必须去
You must.
那些士兵很快会回来的
The soldiers will be back soon.
爸爸
Father!
一旦找到他 所有的士兵都会来追我
When I find him, the soldiers will all come after me.
到时就是你们离开的最佳时机
That makes you the best chance to get out of woods.
他要去哪里
Where is he going?!
凯撒 凯撒
Caesar! Caesar!
那些士兵的营地一直在转移
The soldiers' camp is always moving.
我的手下知道他们在哪儿
My guards think they know where it is.
- 我带你去 - 你需要我的支援
- Let me take you. - You need me to back you up!
不
No!
求你了 我知道失去儿子是什么感觉
Please... I know what it's like to lose a son.
我可能没法活着回去
I may not make it back.
所以我才要跟着你
That's why I'm coming.
确保你能安全回来
To make sure you do.
我的手下认为士兵就在这儿 总是有火在烧
Guards think soldiers here... Always fires burning.
这里没人
No one here.
四处搜一下
Search the area.
我只是放下手上的东西
Just gonna put this down.
他一个人在这儿干吗
What's he doing out here alone?
或许他是个逃兵
Maybe he's a deserter?
到处看看
Look around.
能用的都带走
Take what you can.
她有点不对劲 我想她不会说话
Something wrong with her. I don't think she can speak.
走吧
Come.
她一个人在这儿会死的
She'll die out here alone.
我们不能带上她 毛里斯
We cannot take her, Maurice.
我理解 可我不能丢下她
I understand... But I cannot leave her.
只有死了的金刚才是好金刚
找到上校了吗
Did you find the Colonel?
没有
No.
温特
Winter.
驴子
上校在哪里
Where is the Colonel?
- 他走了  - 走了
- He's gone. - Gone?
今天早上走的 带了许多人一起
He left this morning, took many men with him.
还会有更多士兵从北方过来
More soldiers are coming down from the North.
上校打算去边界和他们会合
The Colonel is going to meet them at the border.
什么边界 为什么
What border? Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
不过我们明天会跟着去
But the rest of us are going tomorrow.
驴子们觉得北方的这些士兵
Donkeys think the soldiers from the North
是来彻底消灭猿类的
are coming to help finish off the apes for good.
那天 就在山上那一战之后
That day, after the battle on the hill,
我们抓住的那只驴子向我保证 上校会饶我一命
the donkey we caught promised me the Colonel would spare my life
只要我告诉他们你藏在哪里
if I told them where you were hiding.
原谅我
Forgive me!
我的儿子
My son...
我的妻子
My wife...
全都死了
are dead.
现在该怎么办
Now what do we do?
等士兵们出发
Wait till the soldiers go...
跟着他们去找上校
Follow them to the Colonel.
科巴
Koba?
猿类不杀猿类
Ape not kill ape.
士兵们要离开了
The soldiers are leaving!
他们停下了
They stopped.
他们在朝谁开枪
What are they shooting at?
不知道
I don't know.
他们为什么朝你们开枪
Why did they shoot you?
和她一样
Like her!
他说不出话来
He cannot speak!
伤势那么重 他会死的
He will die of those wounds.
卢卡
Luca.
那些士兵去哪儿了
Where did the soldiers go?!
温特说他们会去某个边界
Winter said they were going to a border.
没错 可往哪条路走呢
Yes but which way is that?!
坏 猴子
Bad... ape.
Bad ape.
你是谁
Who are you?
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我想他不懂我们的意思
I don't think he understands.
我不认识他 他不是我们的一员
I don't recognize him. He's not one of us.
只有你一个吗
Are you alone here?
冷
Cold?
Cold.
我看见女孩儿 以为你们是人类
I see girl. I think you human.
原来你们是猿类 和我一样
But you ape. Like me!
不 不 不要动
No, no. Put down.
- 你待在这里多久了  - 很久了 很久很久
- How long have you been here? - Long time. Long... long time.
家
Home.
我以前的家
Old home.
西拉动物园
你还有同伴吗
Are there more like you?
- 动物园里其他的猿类  - 死了 全都死了
- More apes... from zoo? - Dead. All dead.
很久以前 人类生病了
Long time. Human get sick.
猿类变聪明了
Ape get smart.
然后人类杀死猿类 可我没被杀
Then human kill ape. But not me.
我跑了
I run.
- 你学会了说话  - 听人类说
- You learned to speak? - Listened human.
坏猴子
"Bad ape!"
Bad ape.
不
No.
不要碰
No touch.
那个是我的
That's mine.
我没事
I'm okay.
真了不起
Amazing...
我还以为只有我们会说话
Always thought we were the only ones.
不知道世上还有没有其他
Wonder if there are more in the world?
像我们一样的猿类
More apes like us.
来 吃啊 吃
Here. Eat. Eat.
新朋友
New friends.
特殊的日子
Special day.
加利福尼亚边界检疫站 塔岩
边界
这是从哪儿弄来的
Where did you get this?
坏地方
Bad place.
我很久以前找到的 离开动物园后我寻找食物
I find long time ago. After zoo I look for food.
我发现了人类动物园
I find human zoo.
全都是生病的人
Zoo for sick.
很高的墙 生病的人 爬墙
Big walls. Sick human climb.
坏人类 杀他们
Bad human kill.
然后 所有人都生病
And then all get sick.
所有人都死了 很久以前 很久很久
All dead now. Long time. Long time.
坏人类
Bad humans?
士兵吗
Soldiers?
- 士兵  - 一个废弃的军营
- Soldiers. - A deserted military camp!
就在边界
On the border!
或许上校和军队就是去那儿了
Maybe the Colonel and the troops are going there?
那儿离这儿远吗 你能带我们去吗
Is it far? Can you take us?
人类动物园
Human zoo?
不 不 不回那儿去
No! No go back there. I...
所有人都死了 我才来这儿 这儿非常安全
Everyone dead. I come here. Very safe here.
不要回去
Never go back! No!
- 求你了 你必须带我们去那儿  - 不
- Please. You must take us. - No!
不 不能去 不能去 不 不
No! Cannot take! Cannot take! No, no!
不 看啊 看啊
No! Look! Look! Look!
很多雪 不能走 留在这儿
More snow. Cannot go. Must stay.
你能吃 你能休息 和我一起 留在这儿
You eat, you rest, stay here. With me.
给 给你
Here. You keep.
给她了
She keep.
诺娃
是谁
Who is...
那孩子
child?
我不知道
I don't know.
可她跟着你
But she with you?
她没有别的同伴了
She has no one else.
我刚才看你看着她
I see you look at her just now.
眼神很悲伤
Look sad.
你也有孩子吗
You have child?
一个
One.
另一个被人类杀死了
The other was killed by human.
士兵吗
Soldier?
我
I...
也有孩子
Had child.
你觉得人类动物园里
You think you will find him...
能找到他吗
at human zoo?
那个士兵
Soldier?
我不知道
I don't know.
或许吧
Maybe.
那么
Then...
那我带你去吧
Maybe I take you.
口渴
Thirsty.
走 卢卡 我们靠近点
Luca, come. Let's go closer.
保护好他们
Keep them safe.
他们在干吗
What are they doing?
不知道
I don't know.
那是什么 巡逻队吗
What's that? A patrol?
马上没有人
I don't see riders.
别动
Hold it!
我看到他们过来了
I saw them coming.
至少这次
At least this time...
我保护了你
I was able to protect you...
凯撒
Caesar...
该停下了
This must stop.
现在回去找大家还不迟
It's not too late to join the other apes.
我们不能回头
We cannot turn back!
卢卡献出了自己的生命
Luca gave his life.
求你了
Please!
他们必须付出代价
They must pay.
现在的你
Now...
听起来就像科巴
you sound like Koba.
带你们一起来就是个错误
It was a mistake bringing you all.
这是我的战争
This is my fight.
我必须一个人去了结了它
I will finish this alone.
回去 快
Go. Now.
去找大部队
Join the others.
发生了什么事
What happened?
他们突然出现
They came out of nowhere...
攻击了我们
Attacked us.
我们以为他们会把我们通通杀死
We thought they would kill us all...
但上校阻止了他们
But the Colonel stopped them!
他眼神里流露着疯狂
There was madness in his eyes!
他说要在我们死之前好好利用我们
He said they would use us, before we died!
于是他们就把我们全都带到了这里
And they brought us all here!
利用你们
Use you?
他们逼迫我们干活
They've been forcing us to work!
什么
What...
让你们干什么样的活儿
What kind of work?
等等 我的儿子 他在这儿吗
Wait. My little son is here.
格兰特
Grant...
和李
and Lee.
惠林顿
Wellington...
和拿破仑
and Napoleon.
卡斯特
Custer
还有酋长坐牛
and Sitting Bull...
你可能没怎么看过书吧
You’re probably not much of a reader,
不过眼下可是一个非常重要的时刻
but this is a big moment.
你躲哪儿去了
Where were you?
我们很走运 遇上了你的猴群
We came upon your herd. We got lucky.
不过我很惊讶 你居然没和他们一起
I was surprised you weren’t with them.
我希望你没有后悔之前放他一条生路
I hope you don’t come to regret sparing his life.
他射得很准
He's quite a good shot.
你最终还是来救你的族群了吗
Have you finally come to save your apes?
我是冲你来的
I came for you.
冲我？
For me?
那晚我杀死的是谁
Who did I kill that night?
我的妻子
My wife.
还有我的儿子
My son.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我的目标是你
I was there for you.
我的天啊
God.
看看你的眼睛
Look at your eyes.
简直和人类一样
Almost human.
- 你怎么知道我在这儿的  - 我收到消息 你会来这儿
- How did you know I was here?  - I was told you were coming.
北方还会有更多士兵
That more soldiers from the north...
- 会来这里和你会合  - 和我汇合
- would be joining you here.  - Joining me?
为了把我们猿类
To finish us off.
一举歼灭
For good.
谁这么告诉你的
Who told you that?
好吧
Okay.
我们走
Let's go.
爸爸
Father!
蕾可
Lake.
原谅他们 我们经历了太多
Forgive them. We've been through much.
爸爸
Father!
我到底做了些什么
What have I done?
全体都有 立定
Battalion, halt!
- 鲜血  - 可以滋养青草
- Blood!  - Makes the grass grow!
- 我们  - 可以献出鲜血
- We!  - Make the blood flow!
- 我们既是开始  - 也是终结
- We are the beginning!  - And the end!
♫ 美国国歌《星条旗》♫
危险 易燃
到这儿以后我们就没吃过东西没喝过水
We haven't had food or water since we got here...
他们为什么要建这堵墙
Why do they need a wall?
驴子
Donkey!
- 教训他  – 好的
- Get him! - Okay, okay.
好的
Okay.
别再打了
Leave him!
- 告诉他们全都回去干活  – 我们需要食物和水
- Tell them to get back to work. - Apes need food and water.
- 告诉他们  – 给他们食物和水
- Tell them. - Give them food and water.
五
Five.
四
Four.
三
Three.
二
Two.
快回去干活
Hurry! Back to work!
把他绑起来 驴子
String him up, donkey.
坏地方
Bad place.
很坏 很坏的地方
Bad, bad place.
看到了什么
What you see?
- 必须救他们  – 怎么救
- Must save them! - But how?
想想 凯撒他会怎么做
Must think! What would Caesar do?
不
No!
怎么这么小
Why so small?
上校答应了你什么
What did the Colonel promised you?
你真觉得等我们全都死了
You really think he let you live?
他会放过你吗
After we are gone?
你让他们叫你驴子
You let them call you donkey.
可你是猿类
You are ape.
上校要见你
Colonel wants see you.
历史
再敢妨碍他们干活
Interfere with the work again,
我就把他们一个个全都杀掉
I will begin slaughtering the apes, one by one.
听懂了吗 我需要那堵墙
Understand? I need that wall.
猿类需要食物还有水
Apes need food and water.
当任务完成后 我自然会给他们食物和水
They'll get food and water when they finish their work.
给他们食物和水
Give apes food and water.
- 否则任务没法完成  – 你太过感情用事了
- Or they cannot finish it. - You know, you're very emotional.
你凭什么觉得你有资本和我讨价还价
What makes you think you’re in a position to make demands?
- 好了 我们走  – 北方来的那些士兵
- Okay, let's go. - The soldiers who are coming here,
并不是来和你们会合的 对吧
they are not coming to join you, are they?
我看到外墙上的那些士兵正在准备作战
I saw men outside, on the wall, preparing for battle.
他们都说你很聪明 不过想不到那么聪明
They told me you're smart, but that's impressive.
对 他们并不是来会合的
No, they won't be joining me.
他们是你的敌人吗
They are against you?
他们怕我
They fear me.
为什么 因为你连自己人也杀吗
Why? Because you kill your own men?
我们发现了尸体
We found bodies.
那几个人很不对劲
Something wrong with these men.
天啊 你还真是让我大开眼界
Jesus Christ, you are impressive.
现在你全都知道了 你肯定觉得我不是好人
You paint quite a picture. What you must think of me.
我觉得你没有怜悯之心
I think you have no mercy.
你来是为了杀我
You came here to kill me.
你会对我有怜悯之心吗
Were you going to show me mercy?
我放过了你的人 这就是我对你的怜悯
I showed you mercy when I spared your men.
我提出了和平相处 可你却杀了我的家人
I offered you peace and you killed my family.
怜悯
Mercy.
你知道你所谓的怜悯给我们带来了什么
Do you have any idea what your mercy would do to us?
你们比我们强壮
You’re much stronger than we are.
你们聪明绝顶
You're smart as hell.
不管你们怎么说 你们终将替代我们
No matter what you say, you’d eventually replace us.
这是大自然的法则
That’s the law of Nature.
讽刺的是 是我们造就了你们
The irony is, we created you.
我们不断挑战自然 试图征服它
We tried to defy Nature, bend it to our will.
于是大自然开始惩罚我们的自以为是
And Nature’s been punishing us for our arrogance ever since.
十个月前 我派了侦查小组去找你们的营地
Ten months ago, I sent out recon units to look for your base.
我的儿子是其中一个小组的成员
My own son was a soldier with one of the units.
有一天他突然就不说话
One day he suddenly stopped speaking.
退化成非常原始的状态 就像动物一样
He became primitive, like an animal.
他们跑来告诉我
They contacted me,
说我的儿子疯了
said that they thought he’d lost his mind,
说他承受不住战争的压力
that the war was too much for him.
然后照顾他的那些人也不会说话了
Then the man who cared for him stopped speaking too.
当时的医生提出了一个理论 在他还会说话时
Their medic had a theory, before he stopped speaking,
即使是幸存者身上也同样携带着
that the virus that almost wiped us out,
这种让人类几乎濒临灭绝的可怕病毒
the virus that every human survivor still carries,
现在病毒突变了
had suddenly changed.
变异了
Mutated.
如果传播开来的话 这次人类将会彻底灭亡
And if it spread, it would destroy humanity for good this time.
它不会杀死我们 但会夺走那些使我们成为人类的东西
Not by killing us, but by robbing us of the things that make us human.
我们的语言 我们的思想
Our speech, our higher thinking.
它会把我们变成野兽 你还在这儿和我谈怜悯
It would turn us into beasts. You talk about mercy?
换作你会怎么做
What would you have done?
当时有那么一刻我非常清醒
It was a moment of clarity for me.
我意识到我必须牺牲自己唯一的儿子
I realized that I would have to sacrifice my only son,
这样人类才能得以保全
so that humanity could be saved.
当时我握着那把枪很久很久
I held that gun in my hand for a long time...
我拿它指着我唯一的儿子
And I pointed it at my only child.
他看着我 眼睛里充满了信任
He looked at me with trust in his eyes.
即便从他原始的眼神中
Even in his primitive gaze,
我也感受到了
I felt his...
他的爱
love.
我扣下了扳机
I pulled the trigger.
我感觉被净化了 也让我的目标变得更加明确
It purified me. It made my purpose clear.
我下令杀死了其他受到感染的人 所有人
I gave orders to kill the others infected, all of them.
把他们的东西 任何可能会传播病毒的东西全都烧掉
Burn their belongings, anything that might spread contamination.
有些人质疑我的判断力
Some of the men questioned my judgment.
我让他们做出和我一样的选择
I was asking them to do what I had done,
牺牲他们的朋友们 他们的家人
to sacrifice their friends, their family.
当然 他们拒绝了
Of course, they refused.
所以我把他们也杀了
I had them killed too.
有些带着孩子的 偷偷逃进了树林里
Others with children deserted into the woods.
其中有个家伙逃到了我在北方的上级那里
One of those cowards fled to my superiors up north.
他们试图说服我
They tried to convince me
这场瘟疫可以通过医疗手段得以控制
that this plague could be dealt with medically.
那时我知道 经历了那么多之后 他们还是什么都没学到
That’s when I realized that they had learned nothing from our past.
你把他们也杀了
You killed them too?
我是怎么做的来着 普里彻
What did I do, Preacher?
你砍下了他们的头 长官
You severed their heads, sir.
除了被我放走的那个
Except for the one I spared
我让他回去替我送个口信
so he could return and deliver a message.
如果他们想要卸下我的指挥权
If they wanted to relieve me of my command,
就得来这里找我 然后亲自动手
they’d have to meet me here, and do it themselves.
这里曾经是个军械库
This used to be a weapons depot.
在猿流感刚开始时 他们把这里改造成了一个军营
They turned it into a relocation camp when the crisis was just beginning.
不过武器还在这里 就在山里面
But the weapons are all still here, inside the mountain.
会有多少人到这里来
How many men will be coming?
或许会倾巢而出
Probably all of them.
不过别想动坏脑筋
But don’t get any ideas,
除了我 能让他们更害怕的 就只有你们猿类了
the only thing they fear more than me is you apes.
这是一场圣战
This is a holy war.
所有人类历史都指向这一刻
All of human history has led to this moment.
如果我们输了 我们将成为最后的人类
If we lose, we’II be the last of our kind.
我们的地球会成为你们的猩球 而我们也会成为你们的牲口
It will be a planet of apes, and we’II become your cattle.
看看你
Look at you.
你觉得我疯了 对吧
You think I am sick, don't you?
我其实并不想杀你儿子
I didn’t mean to kill your son.
但如果他注定会继承你邪恶的王国
But if his destiny was to inherit your unholy kingdom...
我很高兴我了结了他
I am glad I did.
退后
Get back!
我就说你太感情用事了
So emotional!
我知道你内心非常纠结
I see how conflicted you are.
你已经搞不清自己的目标了
You are confused in your purpose.
你对我的所作所为感到愤怒 但这就是战争
You’re angry at me for something I did that was an act of war.
但现在你已经注入了太多私人恩怨
But you’re taking this all much far too personally.
动动你的脑子 如果你杀了我
What do you think my men would have done to your apes,
我的人会怎么处置你的同类
if you had killed me?
还是说杀了我对你来说更重要
Or is killing me more important?
到处都是士兵 我们要怎么进去
Soldiers everywhere! How will we get in?
得想办法进去 必须得进去
Must get in somehow... Must get in!
要进去吗
In? In?
不
No!
不能进去 不
No go in! No!
朋友 朋友 不能进去
Friends! Friends! No! No go in!
不能进去
No go in!
朋友 朋友
Friend! Friend!
谢谢 谢谢 朋友
Thank you. Thank you, friend.
你救了我们的命
You save our lives!
逃出地狱之路
生了病的人类 肯定就是从这里逃走的
Sick humans must have escaped down here!
不 不 不 别 别爬 别
No, no! No, no climb! No!
什么 你看到了什么
What? What you see?
我们在哪里
Wonder where we are.
猴灾泛滥
哦 不 朋友
No! Friend...
不
No!
不 不
No! No!
不 回来 回来
No! Come, come!
回来 回来 回来
Come! Come, come.
不 回来
No! Come!
回来 回来 快回来
Come! Come, come!
科巴
Koba...
睡吧
Sleep.
你救不了他们的
You cannot save them.
猿类都将死在这里
Apes all die here.
- 不会的  - 会的
- No! - Yes.
跟我走吧
Join me...
如果明早他还活着的话
If he's still alive in the morning...
就让他回去和其他猿类一起干活
He goes back to work as everyone else.
不然就杀了他
Or you shoot him.
快来 快来 快来
Come. Come. Come.
她到里面去了
She go in!
渴吗
Thirsty?
躲起来 快
Hide. Quick.
人类会杀了她的
Humans will kill her!
我知道该怎么做 你们快走
I know what to do! Go!
你还有其他同伴吗
Are there others out there?
搜查附近一带
Sweep the area.
把他关进围栏里
Put him in the pen.
感觉好点了吗
Feeling better?
那就好 那我们可以计划逃跑的事了
Good. Then we can talk about escape.
团结才会强大
Apes together strong!
- 我们既是开始  - 也是终结
- We are the beginning! - And the end!
居然还活着
Still alive.
让他单独去采石场
Send him to the quarry. Alone.
等等
Hold on.
这是什么
What is this?
怎么会出现在这里
How did this get in there?
带他去干活
Get him to work.
Thirty-seven.
Fifty-five.
到大伙儿的笼子需要37步
Thirty-seven steps to the adult cage.
到孩子们那儿需要55步
Fifty-five to the children.
你知道 等到墙建好了 上校就会杀了所有猿类
You know, Colonel shoot apes when wall is done.
这墙是疯狂之举
This wall is madness.
根本救不了他
It won't save him.
就像它同样也救不了你
Anymore than it will save you.
我自己会救我自己
I save myself.
你身上还有什么值得被拯救吗
Is there anything left of you to save?
我挖的
I do.
大家都回到笼子里了吗
Apes going back to the cage?
你 非常勇敢
You are very brave.
- 勇敢？ - 勇敢
- Brave? - Brave!
勇敢
Brave!
猿类？
Ape?
我 是猿类吗
Me? Ape?
你是
You are...
诺娃
Nova.
来 来 快来看看
Come! Come! Come to see!
过来看
Come to see!
来 快来看
Come! Come to see!
34，35，36，37！30！37！
34, 35, 36, 37! 30! 37!
我挖的
I do.
现在怎么办
What now?
干吗
What?
不
No!
不 不 不 不
No, no! No, no!
好吧
Okay.
这就是我和你们提到的那个同类
This is the ape I told you about!
谢谢你
Thank you.
坏猴子
Bad Ape.
坏...猴子
Bad... Bad Ape.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
不能继续挖了 不然整个隧道都会被水淹没的
We can't keep digging! It will flood the whole tunnel!
可不挖我们就没法到孩子们那里
If we don't, we can't reach the children!
我们必须时刻关注下面的情况
We must keep looking down there...
另找办法到孩子们那儿去
Find another way to reach the children.
我们必须马上离开 会有更多士兵到这里来
We must leave now! More soldiers are coming!
人类会相互残杀 也会杀死我们
Humans will destroy each other! And us with them!
只能从地面把孩子们救出来
We’II have to get the children out above ground.
怎么救
How?
你们这些畜生
You animals!
是谁干的
Who did that?
到底是谁
Who was it?
是不是你
Was it you?
我爱你 儿子
I love you, son.
走 快走
Go, go.
快点 我们走
Hurry! Let's go!
凯撒 怎么了
Caesar, what's wrong?
赶紧 你快走吧
Hurry. You must go.
留下你一个吗
Without you?
不行
No.
毛里斯说得对
Maurice was right.
现在的我就像科巴
I am like Koba.
他当年不能放下他的仇恨
He could not escape his hate.
我现在也无法放下我的
And I still cannot escape mine.
走 快走 快走
Move! Go, go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
上校 上校
Colonel! Colonel!
他到底人在哪里
Where the hell is he?
快点
Hurry up!
上校 你在里面吗 上校
Colonel, are you in there? Colonel?
驴子 去拿榴弹发射器
Donkey! Grenade launcher!
你在搞什么鬼 蠢驴 把发射器给我
God damn it, donkey! Get me the launcher!
开始及结束
别担心
Don't worry.
毛里斯
Maurice...
你们现在都到家了
You are home now.
猿类很强大
Apes are strong...
不管有没有我
With or without me.
儿子会知道
Son will know...
谁是他的父亲
who was father.
还有
And what...
凯撒
Caesar did...
为我们做的一切
for us.
凯撒
Caesar...